Chun-Yu, Chen (Aloha)

18/F A4, Bayview Mansion No.21 Moreton Terrace Causeway Bay, Hong Kong Email: y.alohac@gmail.com Phone: +886 937206415

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alohacc

Github: https://github.com/alChaCC

Blog: http://ccaloha.cc

Senior Full Stack Developer

Full Stack Enterprise Web Development - Agile/Dev Ops Development Practice

Over 5 years qualified working experience in software development, included 3 years in Ruby on Rails development especially in E-commerce, logistic and content-based websites and 3 years in system integration testing. Participated more than 10+ projects as main developer included mircoservice, global api and a open source project. I'm self-motivated and have a passionate mind. Plus, I'm really good at learning and solving problem. I'm looking for a challenging role that utilizes my previous skills and experiences especially in Web/Application development.

Technical Skill Set

Programming Language	Databases	Open API / 3rd Party	Other Technologies
• Ruby / Ruby on Rails	• PostgreSQL	 AWS MWS/Ebay/ Shopify 	• Linux
• JavaScripts	• MySQL	Google Analytics	• Git
• R	• MongoDB	 Google Tag Manager 	• CSS
		• Facebook API / Ads	• D3.js

Professional Experience

Easyship Fulfilment Services Ltd, Hong Kong Senior Full Stack Developer

2016/01 – present

Improving system architecture and integrate with most popular E-commerce platforms and couriers. Built a MVP product as a total solution for E-commerce and logistic problem.

• As a Senior developer, working in a startup company oversea, I start to contribute codes in a week after I joined the company, refactoring CSV upload to support multi-formats and make it easy to maintain and extend. I separated rate calculation from main project using microservice architecture. Built apps in Shopify App Store for in-cart rate calculation. And we built a MVP product to streamline E-commerce cross platform and logistic process.

i-True Communications inc, Taiwan Lead Ruby on Rails developer

2014/07 - 2016/01

It was my responsibility to help ITs and operators solving their critical problems and to study new technology for our company next-generation products and make it happen.

- As a lead developer, I design and implement most of our core products such as the largest cosmetic and beauty product community website in Taiwan (70% core function are written by me included administrator panel, authorization, email tracking, product weekly rankings, performance of marketing campaigns...etc) and a data manage platform for AD retargeting.
- As a researcher, I have to learn new technology and share with not only IT but also other employees. For example, I open a 6 months class for google analytics in weekly company meeting. Plus, I'm working with data at scale with MongoDB and building up a behavior tracking system and its administrator panel system. And I use map-reduce and aggregation for accelerating pageviews extraction and audience classification.
- As a data scientist, I use R and D3.js to analyze reviews data and using text segmentation, scikit-learn to build up a BI system for finding the relationship between keywords and cosmetic products, which will be used in recommendation system and data management platform.

• As a systems engineer, By using AWS, I set up a Ruby on Rails production and staging environment in AWS. Also, I use Route53 for domain routing, S3 for assets uploading, RDS for our MySQL database, ELB for distributing workloads and EC2 for search engine and schedule jobs.

i-True Commerce inc, Taiwan Ruby on Rails developer

2014/01 - 2014/07

Working in a 4 person start up company, my obligation is to maintain and develop the online cosmetic-box subscription website and support everything.

- As an only one developer, I maintain and develop an easy CRM analytics system for increasing sales by finding who has higher possibility subscribing box. And I introduce Google Tag Management into our website.
- * As a supporter, I participate all strategic marketing meetings and implement application to support marketing idea. This included using Facebook API to find out who send message in our fan page and give him a gift and building a javascript game: winwheel that user can use reward point to play and get a gift.

Freelancer 2013/11 – present

Full Stack Web Developer

To understand client's requirements then quickly and correctly provide a Web application solution.

- As a developer, I build up a fashion and beauty E-commerce website included Google Analytics Enhanced E-commerce Tracking, On/off the shelf on schedule, Discount system, CRM feature, Coupon, Search engine using Sunspot, Payment with credit card or ATM, Email ...etc. Plus, I work with clients building a ERP system especially for fashion and beauty industry.
- As a systems engineer, I set up and maintain a Ruby on Rails production environment using Ubuntu server and use Monit to monitor systems.
- As a volunteer and consultant, I architect and implement a crowdfunding website for Green Dot Communities, a company that installs free rooftop solar panels for old age homes.

ITRI Cloud Computing Center for Mobile Application, Taiwan Software Engineer

2010/11 - 2013/9

My responsibility is to conduct software testing, test automation and support building TaaS for continuous integration.

- As a Quality Assurance Engineer, I mainly responsible for storage testing included Data Main Storage, Data Second Storage and Wide Area Data Backup.
- As a Software Engineer, in order to execute acceptance tests after code daily builds, I exhibit the first automated testing applied in command line interface test plan. After that, our team entered the automated era. Plus, I build up a automated testing using Robotframework, Selenium, shell script and Python) and integrate Jenkins, SpiraTest and Jira for continuous integration.

Education and Training

Education:

2004-2008 2008-2010 National United University: Bachelor of Science, Electrical and Electronics Engineering National Taiwan University: Master of Science. Biomedical Electronics and Bioinformatics

• In order to predict optical parameters such as the scattering coefficient, oxygen saturation and hemoglobin concentration, I used 2 models - the forward model and the inverse model. I implemented the Monte Carlo scaling method by using C++ as forward method. The inverse model used the Levenerg-Marquardt least square method to fit our simulated spectrum. For streamline the research, I built a convenient graphic user interface integrated with Matlab and C++

Others

Patent 張庭嘉, 陳俊宇, 吳延文, "行動裝置及利用行動裝置執行互動遊戲之方法 PORTABLE APPARATUS AND

METHOD FOR PLAYING INTERACTIVE GAMES BY PORTABLE APPARATUS" Taiwan. I488052.

filed June 11, 2015.

Certifications Google Analytics - Google, June 2015 to December 2016